Guide to the Comic Book and Graphic Novel Collection, 1938-2012 RL.00247
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Comic Books and Graphic Novels, 1938-2012, 36 boxes
  - Pic et Nic et Cendrillon: Le Magazine des Jeunes: Editions Lenoir, 1946 (Box 25)
    An. 4 no. 4, 6-14, 16, 18. Published in France; features comic strip "Wamba, Le Justicier de la Brousse" (features African or African-American characters).
  - Jade City Chronicles, Volume 1: The Super Spectacular Bad Ass Herald M.F. Jones: Cypher Comics, Undated (2011?) (Box 26)
    Vol. 1. Local writer.
  - Today's Comix of Politics and People: Today's Comix, 1974 (Box 26)
    Vol. 1, Issues 2-3, 5-6.
  - Vigil: Innovative Corporation, 1992 (Box 26)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-2; Vol. 2, Issue 1.
  - Vigil: Kukulkan: Innovative Corporation, 1993 (Box 26)
    Vol. 1, Issue 1.
  - Vigil: Vamporum Animaturi: Millennium Publications, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Vigil, Collection 1: Fall From Grace: Millennium Publications, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Vigil: Rebirth: Millennium Publications, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Vigil: Desert Foxes: Millennium Publications, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Vigil: Road Trips: Millennium Publications, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Vigil: Eruption: Millennium Publications, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Vigil: Scattershots: Duality Press, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Vigil: Bloodline: Duality Press, 1997-1998 (Box 26)
  - Black Hole: Kitchen Sink Press, 1995 (Box 26)
  - From Hell: Mad Love Publishing, 1992-1994 (Box 26)
    Volumes 1-4.
  - Leave It To Chance: Homage Comics, 1996-1998 (Box 26)
    Issues 1-11. 2 copies of Issue 5.
  - Axis Mundi: Amaze Ink, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Reid Fleming: World's Toughest Milkman: Eclipse Comics, 1986, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
    Vol. 1, Issue 1; Vol. 2, Issues 2-4.
  - Dinosaurs For Hire: Eternity Comics, 1988-1990 (Box 26)
    Issues 2, 5-9. Eternity is a division of Malibu Graphics.
  - Dinosaurs For Hire: Malibu Comics, 1993 (Box 26)
    Issues 1-7. Continuation of previous series.
  - Stray Bullets: El Capitan Books, 1995-1998 (Box 26)
    Issues 1-16.
  - Illegal Alien: Kitchen Sink Press, 1994 (Box 26)
  - A1 True Life Bikini Confidential: Atomeka Press, 1990 (Box 26)
    Book 1, Volume 1.
  - A1: Atomeka Press, 1991 (Box 26)
    Issues 3, 5. Issue 3 undated.
  - The Residents: Freak Show: Dark Horse Comics, 1992 (Box 26)
    One-shot. Inspired by concept album.
  - Mister: Caliber Comics, 1996 (Box 26)
    Vol. 3, Issue 1.
  - Action Planet: Action Planet Comics, 1996-1997 (Box 26)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-3.
  - Bizarre Heroes: Fiasco Comics, 1995-1996 (Box 26)
    Issues 12, 15-17.
  - Astonishing Excitement: All Jonh Comics, 1995-1996 (Box 26)
    Issues 501-502.
  - The Astonishing Moth: Big Jolt Comics, 1996 (Box 26)
  - The Book of Ballads and Sages: Green Man Press, 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - Ebony Warrior: ANIA/Africa Rising, 1993 (Box 27)
    Issue 1. Features African or African-American characters.
  - HERU, Son of Ausar: ANIA/Afrocentric Comic Books, 1993 (Box 27)
  - Ultraman: Ultracomics, 1993 (Box 27)
    Issues 1-3. 2 copies each of Issues 1-2; 1 copy each of Issues 1-3 is a sleeved "Virgin Cover Edition" with a Mutant Monster Trading Card.
  - Ultraman: Nemesis Comics, 1994 (Box 27)
    Issues -1, 1, 3. Continuation of above series; Nemesis and Ultracomics are both imprints of Harvey Comics.
  - Wicked: Millennium Publications, 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Heartstopper: Millennium Publications, 1994 (Box 27)
  - The Tiger Woman: Millennium Publications, 1994 (Box 27)
  - The Adventures of Aaron: Chiasmus, 1994 (Box 27)
    Issue 1. Based on a musical.
  - Jay & Silent Bob: Oni Press, 1998 (Box 27)
  - Clerks: The Comic Book: Oni Press, 1998 (Box 27)
  - Oni Double Feature: Oni Press, 1998 (Box 27)
    Issues 1-3. Issue 1 includes Jay & Silent Bob story.
  - St. Swithin's Day: Oni Press, 1998 (Box 27)
  - True Swamp: Oni Press, 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Spectacles: Alternative Press, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Wandering Star: Pen and Ink Comics/Sirius Comics, 1993-1997 (Box 27)
    Issues 1-21. Series transitions to Sirius Comics starting with Issue 12.
  - Glory: Avatar Press, 2001 (Box 27)
  - Powers: Image Comics, 2000-2002 (Box 27)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1, 3-19.
  - Powers Annual: Image Comics, 2001 (Box 27)
  - Promethea: America's Best Comics, 1999-2002 (Box 27)
    Issues 1-20.
  - Top 10: America's Best Comics, 1999-2001 (Box 27)
  - Tom Strong: America's Best Comics, 1999-2002 (Box 27)
  - Tom Strong's Terrific Tales: America's Best Comics, 2002 (Box 28)
    Issues 1-3. 2 copies of Issue 2.
  - Tomorrow Stories: America's Best Comics, 1999-2001 (Box 28)
  - 64 Page Giant: America's Best Comics, 2001 (Box 28)
  - Greyshirt: Indigo Sunset: America's Best Comics, 2001-2002 (Box 28)
  - Dusty Star: Image Comics, 1997 (Box 28)
  - After Dark: Millennium Publications, 1995 (Box 28)
  - Bloodchilde: Millennium Publications, 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - Phantom Lady: Verotik Publications, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Doctor Gorpon: Aircel Comics, 1991 (Box 28)
  - Ralph Snart Adventures: Now Comics, 1988, 1990 (Box 28)
    Vol. 3, Issues 3, 6, 17-23.
  - Tyrant: SpiderBaby Grafix & Publications, 1994-1996 (Box 28)
    Issues 1-4. 2 copies (first and second printings) of Issue 1.
  - Ragmop: Planet Lucy Press, 1995-1997 (Box 28)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-10; Vol. 2, Issue 1. 2 copies of Vol. 1, Issue 1 (second is inscribed by author).
  - Kane: Dancing Elephant Press, 1993-1998, 1999-2001 (Box 28)
    Issues 1-16, 18-22, 26-29.
  - Jack Staff: Dancing Elephant Press, 2000 (Box 28)
  - The Replacement God: Amaze Ink, 1995-1996 (Box 28)
  - The Replacement God and Other Stories: Amaze Ink, 1997 (Box 28)
  - Scarlet Thunder: Amaze Ink, 1995 (Box 28)
  - Skeleton Key: Amaze Ink, 1995-1996 (Box 28)
    Issues 1-10.
  - Hilly Rose: Astro Comics, 1995-1996, 1997 (Box 28)
    Issues 1-7, 9. 3 copies each of Issues 1-2
  - Dominique: Family Matters: Caliber Press, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Dominique: Protect and Serve: Caliber Press, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Dominique: Killzone: Caliber Press, 1994 (Box 92)
  - Dominique: White Knuckle Drive: Caliber Press, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Kabuki: Fear the Reaper: Caliber Press, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Kabuki: Dance of Death: London Night Studios, 1995 (Box 29)
  - Kabuki: Circle of Blood: Caliber Press/Caliber Comics, 1995 (Box 29)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-6. 2 copies of Issue 5; series transitions to Caliber Comics at Issue 5
  - Kabuki Color Special: Caliber Comics, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Kabuki: Dreams of the Dead: Caliber Comics, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Kabuki: Masks of the Noh: Caliber Comics, 1996-1997 (Box 29)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-4.
  - Kabuki: Skin Deep: Caliber Comics, 1996-1997 (Box 29)
  - Kabuki: Caliber Comics, 1997-1998 (Box 29)
  - Negative Burn: Caliber Press, 1993, 1994, 1995-1996 (Box 29)
    Vol. 1, Issues 3, 9, 12-13, 16, 18, 20-21, 23-33, 36.
  - Tattoo: Caliber Press, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Milk & Cheese's Other Number One: Slave Labor Graphics, 1992, 1994-1995 (Box 29)
    Issues 2-6. Numbered "Other Number One #1," "3rd Number One #1," "4th Number One #1," "First 2nd Issue #1," and "666".
  - Ash: Event Comics, 1995, 1996 (Box 29)
    Vol. 1, Issue 3; Issue 0.
  - Mysterymen Stories: Dark Horse Comics, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Dragonring: Aircel Comics, 1987 (Box 29)
    Issue 13.
  - The Maximortal: King Hell Press, 1992, 1993 (Box 29)
    Issues 1, 3-4, 6-7.
  - Lethargic Comics: Alpha Productions, 1994-1996 (Box 29)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-14 plus Issue Pi. Issues 1 and 2 combined in one volume; Issues 1-5 plus Pi collected in a slipjacket.
  - Lethargic Lad: Crusade Comics, 1996 (Box 29)
    Issues 2-3.
  - Bioneers: Mirage Publishing, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Stupid Heroes: Mirage Publishing, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Xenotech: Mirage Publishing, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Bone: Cartoon Books, 1992-1998 (Box 30)
    Issues 7-32 and 1993 Holiday Special.
  - Strangers in Paradise: Antarctic Press/Abstract Studio/Homage Comics, 1993-1998 (Box 30)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-11, 13; Vol. 2, Issue 14; Vol. 3, Issues 1-19. Includes second printing of Vol. 1, Issue 1, and 2 copies of Vol. 3, Issue 9; series transitions to Abstract Studio starting with Vol. 1, Issue 2 and to Homage Comics starting with Vol. 3, Issue 1.
  - The Collected Strangers in Paradise: Abstract Studio, 1995 (Box 30)
  - Ship of Fools: Caliber Comics, 1996, 1997 (Box 30)
    Vol. 1, Issues 2, 4.
  - El Gato Negro: Azteca Productions, 1994-1997 (Box 30)
  - War Heroes Classics: Lorne-Harvey Publications, 1991 (Box 30)
  - Ratman 2000: Slave Labor Graphics, 1999 (Box 30)
  - Complex City: Better Comics, 2000-2001 (Box 30)
  - Urban Legends: Dark Horse Comics, 1993 (Box 30)
  - How To Pick Up Girls If You're A Comic Book Geek: 3 Finger Prints, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Non: Red Ink, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Last Kiss: Shanda Fantasy Arts, 2001-2002 (Box 30)
  - Cavewoman Meets Explorers: Basement Comics, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Jungle Tales of Cavewoman: Basement Comics, 1998 (Box 30)
  - Dr. Wonder: Old Town Publishing, 1996-1997 (Box 31)
    Vol. 1, Issues 1-5.
  - Red Calloway's Big Bang: Zoo Arsonist Press, 1995, 1996 (Box 31)
    Issues 1, 4.
  - Ebon: Spearhead Comics, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Dear Julia: Black Eye Publications, 1996-1997 (Box 31)
  - Truer Than True Romance: Watson-Guptill Publications, 2001 (Box 31)
  - Art & Beauty Magazine: Kitchen Sink Press, 1996 (Box 31)
  - Anne Rice's Interview with the Vampire: Innovation, 1991, 1993 (Box 32)
    Issues 1-2, 10.
  - Anne Rice's Queen of the Damned: Innovation, 1991, 1993 (Box 32)
    Issues 1, 3, 10.
  - Black Hole: Kitchen Sink Comix, 1996 (Box 32)
  - A Distant Soil: Image, 1996 (Box 32)
    Issue 15.
  - Don Simpson's Bizzare Heroes: Fiasco Comics, 1994-1995 (Box 32)
    Issues 0-8, 10-11, 13-14.
  - El Gato Negro: Azteca Productions, 1993 (Box 32)
    Issue 1
  - Kabuki: Circle of Blood: Caliber Comics, 1996 (Box 32)
    Issue 6
  - Negative Burn: Caliber Comics, 1996 (Box 32)
    Issue 34
  - Powers: Image, 2002 (Box 32)
    Issue 20
  - Strangers in Paradise: Abstract Studio, 1996 (Box 32)
    Issue 12
  - Top 10: America's Best Comics, 1999 (Box 32)
    Issue 2
  - Latino Comics (Box 33)
    Boxes 33-36 were purchased together as a Latino Comics Collection in 2012. A detailed inventory of these items is available in Box 33 or in the Collection Control File.
    - Rodriguez, Octavio: Comic Book Collection, 2005-2011. (Box 33)
      Ciudad, Issue 1-2. 'Cano Scribbles, 'Cano Scribbles 1-5. The Adventures of Plat and Dave, Issues 1-2. New Beginnings...
    - Rosado, Rafael: Giants Beware! Heroes Come in All Sizes, 2012 (Box 33)
    - Tito na Rua: Street Comics (Box 33)
      Street Comics, Vol. 1, 2011, and The Adventures of Joe Nobody and the Pooch Dog, No. 1-2, 2011.
    - Wishnia, Leah: The Cactus Queen, 2012 (Box 33)
    - Heath, Jennifer: El Repelente (or, the 2012 Antics of Anabela), 2011 (Box 33)
    - Rodriguez, Fernando (Box 33)
      Aztec of the City, Vol. 3 No. 1 (2012 reprint, originally published 1993). Adelita/Tales of Aztlan: The Legend of La Llorona, 2003.
    - Gamboa, Gabby: Zine Collection (Box 33)
      Chris Montez, Teenage Rockstar, 2000. Miss Lonely Hearts 1, 2011.
    - Crespo, Jaime: Zine Collection, 1995-2012 (Box 33)
      Throb. Tortilla No. 1-2. Last Slice (Best of the Last Slices Strips). Slices (Selected Favorites from the Weekly Strip: Slice O'Life).
    - Lano, Mario T., etc.: Reluctant Zero #1, 2011 (Box 34)
    - Aushenker, Michael: Comic Book Collection, 1995-2010 (Box 34)
      Futuresh CK: El Gato 2002. The Nine Lives of El Gato Crime Mangler #1. The Nine Loves of El Gato Crime Mangler. Gumby's Gang Starring Pokey.
    - Leanos, John Jota: Imperial Silence: Una Opera Muerta, 2008 (DVD) (Box 34)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
    - Mayorga Amaya, Liz: Zine Collection, 2010-2012 (Box 34)
      Outgrowing Plastic Dolls. Inked. Virere Ardendo. A Caxcan Guerilla Takes Over the Awkward Girl. The Pigeon Queen.
    - Rodriguez, Grasiela: Lunatic Fringe #1 and Spadra #1, 2010 (Box 34)
    - Rodriguez, Isis, and Alfi Lopez: Ninaji. El Renacimiento, No. 1-2 (Box 34)
    - Hernandez, Javier: El Muerto Collector Box, 2012 (Box 34)
      Includes first issue of El Muerto, DVD of film, and El Muerto doll.
    - Anderson, Brian: Friend of Dorothy, Issues 1-2, 2010 (Box 35)
    - Anderson, Brian, and Celina Hernandez: Reignbow and Dee-Va, Issues 1-3, 2008 (Box 35)
    - Hernandez, Javier: Comic Batch, 2011-2012 (Box 35)
      El Muerto Mishmash. Weapon Tex-Mex vs. El Muerto. The Art of the Coma. Comic Pop!. The Comic Pop Sketchbook. Man Swamp. The Coma. Manga Muerto.
    - Gonzalez, Crystal, 2010-2012 (Box 35)
      Trash and Clash, Issue 1. In the Dark, Issues 1-2.
    - Parada, David: Zotz: Serpent and Shield, Issue 1, 2011 (Box 35)
    - Oropeza, Antonio F.: Amigoman, The Latin Avenger, 3 issues, 2003, 2009, 2012 (Box 35)
    - The Kids of Widney High: Beyond the Sky's Limit!, Issue 1, 2009 (Box 35)
    - Navarro, Rafael: Comic Book Collection, 1997-2012 (Box 35)
      Sonambulo Lives. Strange Tales. Ghost of a Chance. Masks of Sonambulo. Mexican Stand-off (Parts 1-3). Sleep of the Just. Lucha Noir.
    - Cabrera, Jose: Crying Macho Man Collection, 2010-2012 (Box 35)
      Crying Macho Man, Issues 1-4. Prime Cut. You So Loco. Macho and the Gang. The Big Joke Book.
    - Oropeza, Antonio: Amigoman poster collection (10 prints) (Box 36)
    - Mendoza, Rodolfo: Eagle Night Comic, 2012 (Box 36)
    - Cabrera, Jose: Official Poster for Latino Comics Expo, 2012 (Box 36)
    - Cabrera, Jose: Poster set for Latino Comics Expo, 2012 (5 posters) (Box 36)
    - Cabrera, Jose: Crying Macho Man strips, 2007 (8 posters) (Box 36)
    - Hernandez, Javier: Los Comex Collection, 2011-2012 (Box 36)